[
  {
    "question": "Which British monarch reigned the longest?",
    "answer": "Queen Victoria",
    "choice1": "Queen Elizabeth II",
    "choice2": "King George III",
    "choice3": "King Henry VIII",
    "category": "History"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the Great Fire of London occur?",
    "answer": "1666",
    "choice1": "1766",
    "choice2": "1606",
    "choice3": "1566",
    "category": "History"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Prime Minister of the UK during World War I?",
    "answer": "H. H. Asquith",
    "choice1": "David Lloyd George",
    "choice2": "Winston Churchill",
    "choice3": "Neville Chamberlain",
    "category": "History"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which historical figure is associated with the Gunpowder Plot?",
    "answer": "Guy Fawkes",
    "choice1": "Robert Catesby",
    "choice2": "Francis Tresham",
    "choice3": "Walter Raleigh",
    "category": "History"
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did women gain the right to vote in parliamentary elections in the UK (on the same terms as men)?",
    "answer": "1928",
    "choice1": "1918",
    "choice2": "1920",
    "choice3": "1932",
    "category": "History"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who led the suffragette movement in the UK?",
    "answer": "Emmeline Pankhurst",
    "choice1": "Emily Davison",
    "choice2": "Millicent Fawcett",
    "choice3": "Lydia Becker",
    "category": "History"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which king famously had six wives?",
    "answer": "Henry VIII",
    "choice1": "Henry VII",
    "choice2": "Edward VI",
    "choice3": "Charles I",
    "category": "History"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what century was the Magna Carta signed?",
    "answer": "13th Century",
    "choice1": "12th Century",
    "choice2": "14th Century",
    "choice3": "15th Century",
    "category": "History"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which battle marked the Norman conquest of England?",
    "answer": "Battle of Hastings",
    "choice1": "Battle of Agincourt",
    "choice2": "Battle of Bosworth Field",
    "choice3": "Battle of Bannockburn",
    "category": "History"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of Great Britain?",
    "answer": "Robert Walpole",
    "choice1": "William Pitt the Elder",
    "choice2": "Lord North",
    "choice3": "Henry Pelham",
    "category": "History"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which British sitcom features the characters Del Boy and Rodney Trotter?",
    "answer": "Only Fools and Horses",
    "choice1": "The Good Life",
    "choice2": "Open All Hours",
    "choice3": "Keeping Up Appearances",
    "category": "Television"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who plays the Doctor in the most recent series of Doctor Who?",
    "answer": "Ncuti Gatwa",
    "choice1": "Jodie Whittaker",
    "choice2": "David Tennant",
    "choice3": "Matt Smith",
    "category": "Television"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the fictional Yorkshire village in Emmerdale?",
    "answer": "Beckindale",
    "choice1": "Ambridge",
    "choice2": "Weatherfield",
    "choice3": "Walford",
    "category": "Television"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which reality TV show is filmed in the Australian jungle?",
    "answer": "I'm a Celebrity...Get Me Out of Here!",
    "choice1": "Love Island",
    "choice2": "Big Brother",
    "choice3": "The Great British Bake Off",
    "category": "Television"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which comedian hosted the UK version of Taskmaster?",
    "answer": "Greg Davies",
    "choice1": "Alex Horne",
    "choice2": "Romesh Ranganathan",
    "choice3": "David Mitchell",
    "category": "Television"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which popular TV show features the character of Sherlock Holmes?",
    "answer": "Sherlock",
    "choice1": "Luther",
    "choice2": "Line of Duty",
    "choice3": "Broadchurch",
    "category": "Television"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which long-running British soap opera is set in Albert Square?",
    "answer": "EastEnders",
    "choice1": "Coronation Street",
    "choice2": "Hollyoaks",
    "choice3": "Emmerdale",
    "category": "Television"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which British television series features the character of Hyacinth Bucket?",
    "answer": "Keeping Up Appearances",
    "choice1": "Absolutely Fabulous",
    "choice2": "The Vicar of Dibley",
    "choice3": "One Foot in the Grave",
    "category": "Television"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which talent show features judges Simon Cowell, Amanda Holden, and Alesha Dixon?",
    "answer": "Britain's Got Talent",
    "choice1": "The X Factor",
    "choice2": "The Voice UK",
    "choice3": "Strictly Come Dancing",
    "category": "Television"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which British game show, hosted by Bradley Walsh, sees contestants answer questions and try to avoid 'The Chaser'?",
    "answer": "The Chase",
    "choice1": "Tipping Point",
    "choice2": "Pointless",
    "choice3": "Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?",
    "category": "Television"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which British film features a group of unemployed steelworkers who form a male striptease act?",
    "answer": "The Full Monty",
    "choice1": "Billy Elliot",
    "choice2": "Trainspotting",
    "choice3": "Lock, Stock and Two Smoking Barrels",
    "category": "Movies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed the film 'The King's Speech'?",
    "answer": "Tom Hooper",
    "choice1": "Danny Boyle",
    "choice2": "Steve McQueen",
    "choice3": "Guy Ritchie",
    "category": "Movies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which actress played the role of Hermione Granger in the Harry Potter film series?",
    "answer": "Emma Watson",
    "choice1": "Bonnie Wright",
    "choice2": "Helena Bonham Carter",
    "choice3": "Maggie Smith",
    "category": "Movies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which British film tells the story of a young boy who discovers a giant peach?",
    "answer": "James and the Giant Peach",
    "choice1": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory",
    "choice2": "Matilda",
    "choice3": "The BFG",
    "category": "Movies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed the film 'Slumdog Millionaire'?",
    "answer": "Danny Boyle",
    "choice1": "Stephen Daldry",
    "choice2": "Ridley Scott",
    "choice3": "Christopher Nolan",
    "category": "Movies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which British film features the character of Mark Renton, played by Ewan McGregor?",
    "answer": "Trainspotting",
    "choice1": "Shallow Grave",
    "choice2": "28 Days Later",
    "choice3": "The Beach",
    "category": "Movies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which film, directed by Edgar Wright, features a zombie apocalypse in London?",
    "answer": "Shaun of the Dead",
    "choice1": "Hot Fuzz",
    "choice2": "The World's End",
    "choice3": "28 Days Later",
    "category": "Movies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which British actor played the role of James Bond in the film 'Casino Royale'?",
    "answer": "Daniel Craig",
    "choice1": "Pierce Brosnan",
    "choice2": "Timothy Dalton",
    "choice3": "Roger Moore",
    "category": "Movies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which British film tells the story of six unemployed miners who form a male striptease act?",
    "answer": "The Full Monty",
    "choice1": "Brassed Off",
    "choice2": "Billy Elliot",
    "choice3": "Calendar Girls",
    "category": "Movies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which British film is a romantic comedy about a bookshop owner who falls in love with an American actress?",
    "answer": "Notting Hill",
    "choice1": "Love Actually",
    "choice2": "Bridget Jones's Diary",
    "choice3": "Four Weddings and a Funeral",
    "category": "Movies"
  }
]
